早安,兄弟姊妹,父母,祖父母,孩子,年輕人,所有人!
兄弟姊妹,朋友,祖父母,父母,所有小朋友,早安!
早安!
哇,真是太高興了,我們可以讓所有人一起在這裏敬拜神!
我們實在很高興,我們今天可以一起來到這裏,敬拜神!
I remember last time when I was here, it was the Thanksgiving day.
我記得上次來的時候,就是上年的感恩節。
I was so touching to see family members worship together as one big group.
我們見到不同的家庭,就是同一個 unit 一齊去敬拜神,實在令我好感動。
Today I witnessed that again here today.
今天我又再次見到了。
Last time especially, I was so touched that when I see everyone,
the adults are laying hands on the children and youth to say a blessing on them.
上次你記不記得,我們見到有祖父母,有父母,
把祂的手按在我們的小朋友上面去祝福他們。
But it is regardless of if they are blood related.
Some adults, they don't have children around, or youth, they don't have any parents around them.
They still get the blessing from someone in this big family to lay hands on them.
但是這個祝福的關係不止於一個血緣關係,
因為我們知道有一些弟兄姊妹說他們沒有小朋友,
但是他們仍然用他們的手按在下一代,去祝福他們。
That is to show God's love among us like one big family.
Let's say praise the Lord together.
就是這樣見到我們神的祝福在我們中間,我們一起說讚美主。
Praise the Lord.
Very good. And today we are going to do that again.
我們今天也會再次一起去這樣做。
You see that this is not a 禮事。
所以你看到這個不是一個紅包,不是一個禮事。
But you know, I am a children pastor.
I've got all the props and everything here.
但是我是一個傳道人,所以我一向都有齊這些法寶在裡面。
Yeah, that is 法寶, you know.
Traditious stuff.
有很多不同的種類的東西。
So before we worship God together, let's bow down to have a word of prayer.
讓我們一起祈禱。
Dear Father God, you are worthy to be praised.
稱為天父,我們讚美你。
Thank you for giving us a church, that community,
so that we can learn to love and support one another.
多謝你給到我們這個教會的群體,
讓我們學習去愛,去愛你,去愛人。
And we could worship together like a big, big family in Christ.
實在很感恩,在基督裡我們就是一個大家庭一起去敬拜你。
As we open the Bible, please let us learn more of your teaching.
當我們打開你自己給我們的話語,聖經的時候,讓我們學習。
And follow you more closely.
我們亦都可以緊緊地去跟隨你。
We ask for your presence to be with us this morning.
我求你將你的祝福臨下到我們每一個人身上。
Let us worship you with a humble heart.
讓我們用一個謙卑的心去敬拜你。
May you open our heart, our eyes, our ears to receive your precious word.
讓你開我們的心,開我們的眼,開我們的耳朵,
去接受你自己給我們的話語。
We pray in the name of our Lord Jesus Christ.
奉主耶穌基督,聖名以祈求。
We say together, Amen.
When was the last time that you received a personal letter?
你記不記得上一次你什麼時候收到一份真的給你的一封信呢?
These days, we use a lot of email, WhatsApp, WeChat, and all that.
We almost forget the feeling to have a letter, a real letter in our hand.
因為你知道我們很用短信、email,各樣種類,
很久都沒有收到一封有信封寄給你的信了。
I remember the first letter that I got in my hand when I was young.
我記得我小時候,我真的收到一封信,
當我第一封信收到的時候,
I was so happy.
我真的很開心。
So that's why after I became a children pastor at my church, R3C,
當我在成北華基做兒童傳道人的時候,
even though we have around 900 children on our list,
我大概有900個小朋友在我們的list。
But I decided every month I'm going to write down a birthday card
for each one of the students that was having birthday that month.
我當時下定決心,
我就要親自寫一封生日卡給每一個小朋友的。
So that's the birthday card for that birthday boy or girl of the month.
I wrote a note, a handwritten note for them.
這個就是其中一張的卡。
在每一張卡裡面,我真的親手寫上祝福他的說話。
And I put on beautiful stickers on each one of them.
當然,小朋友喜歡貼紙的,
我都把貼紙放在裡面。
And then I put it in the envelope.
然後我就放在信封裡面了。
It was good, I have a helper that helped me at least to print the address.
當然,我又同工幫手把一些地址放上去。
We put the stamp on it and put it in the postage mail.
然後就寄了。
Well, you may ask, why board? Why didn't I give it to them on Sunday?
或者你會問我,為什麼你不簡單,禮拜天就直接給他們呢?
So at least it will save the effort and the money for putting it in the postage mail.
那你又可以省一筆,不用放郵票嗎?
But then, the parents are telling me.
但這些父母他會這樣跟我說。
Every time when the kids are receiving the letter in the postage mail, they were so happy.
每一次他們真的在郵箱裡拿到一封給他們的信,他們真的超開心。
They open it and they read each of the notes that I have handwritten on them.
他們就開來看,然後慢慢逐粒字這樣去讀出來。
It shows them that the children pastor love them.
讓他們知道,他們的兒童傳道人是很愛他們的。
And also God loves them too.
還有神是很愛他們的。
So, how about you?
或者你又怎樣呢?
Do you know that every day we are also receiving a letter?
其實你知不知道我們每一天都收到一封信?
What's that?
That is a letter from God because it is in the Bible.
這個就是神給我們的一封信,就是祂的聖經。
This is God's letter to us every day, every moment.
這個聖經就是神給我們的一封信,給我們每一天的一封信,每一刻的一封信。
Just then we have seen the skit, it is saying that when God is praising us in the Bible,
He always say, "Oh, it is for me."
這個短劇都知道了,當我們看的時候,其實對我們說的說話。
That is for me, but when the Bible is rebuking us and say, "It is for Pastor Ada."
當我們見到一些好的說話,就當然是跟我說了,天父。
但當我們見到一些好像責備人的說話,就當然是跟旁邊的人說了。
For her, not for me.
就是給她的,不是我的。
But in fact, God is the whole Bible, every word is for each one of us.
但如果我們深信聖經是神給我們一封完全的信的時候,其實每一個字都是對我們每一個人說話。
Let me going to tell you a story.
我現在很想跟你們分享一個故事。
That story is called "Sydney and Norman".
這個故事就叫做"Sydney and Norman".
Because one day, they are also receiving a letter from God.
因為這兩個朋友有一天收到神給他們的一封信。
You see, the one that is on the left, that you can see, that is Sydney.
在左邊那位朋友就叫做Sydney。
And the one on the right, that little pig, is called Norman.
右邊那位豬朋友就叫做Norman。
豬朋友,不是豬朋友,是狗友。
So I am going to tell you the story from here.
我很想跟你分享這個故事。
Once, there were two pigs living on the same street.
從前,在這條街裡面住了兩隻豬。
They lived next to each other, but they don't know each other's name.
他們是鄰居,但是他們不知道彼此的名字。
Why?
為什麼呢?
Because the one that is on the right, Norman, always get up early for work.
因為右邊那位Norman,他經常都很早起床就去上班。
But you see, the one on the left, even always have the ketchup mark on the tie,
that is Sydney, always getting up late.
但是左邊那位Sydney,就經常都很晚起床的,
就把衣服弄得很髒。
Norman is a very good pig.
Norman實在是很豬。
Niche and tidy.
很整齊,很清潔。
He always follow all the different rules when he was young at school.
他小時候在學校的時候,就會守秩序。
Get all the awards from school.
在學校是很用功的。
And when he grew up,當他長大的時候,
The boss always pat on his shoulder and say, "Good job, Norman."
他的老闆都跟他說, "好,做得好呀,做得好呀,Norman."
And that's why he thought that,
God must be also very pleased of me, because I am such a good pig.
Norman就覺得,神應該對我都十分驕傲,
我這麼好的豬,對不對?
And then he look down on all the other pigs.
They are not doing well.
其他那些小豬,真的沒有我這麼好的。
Wondering why it is so hard for them to be good.
其實也不是有多難,做好豬,對不對?
不是。
Yes, that's it.
And then there is Sidney.
有這隻豬,Sidney了。
He is such a messy pig.
Sidney真是鬧那麼久。
He always cannot follow any rules, whether it is at school or at work.
或者他在學校,在上班,他都不可以順從,守秩序的。
Always late.
經常都遲到的。
In school, always get sent to the principal office.
在學校,又經常都要被老師send到校長室。
And his boss always complain about him as well.
他的老闆又經常投訴他。
And that's why he thought, oh, I was such a messy and bad pig.
Sidney就說,我真是鬧那麼久,我真是一隻頑皮的豬。
God must be very frustrated with me and rejected me.
神當然對我很失望,祂當然不要我了。
He was very sad and thought that he was a total failure.
其實他自己都很傷心,他覺得自己是一個失敗。
One day, both of them received a mail in the mailbox.
有一日,兩隻豬仔都同樣在信箱收到一封信。
What is it?
是什麼來的呢?
It was an invitation from God.
原來是神發出一個邀請信。
He invited both of them to go to his house at 77 M Street.
原來神邀請他們來到神的自己的家,77號M Street。
Yes, want to talk to each one of them individually.
因為神想對著他們,親自跟他們說些話。
Oh, Sidney was panicking.
Sidney簡直是手抖腳抖。
You have to do this.
He was so panic.
真的很緊張,很害怕。
He thought that it must be God that wants to punish me
and tell me that it's the same thing as I was sent
to the principal's office when I was young.
他心裡只想著,糟糕了,神當然有事要罵我了。
就好像我小時候,老師經常都罵我、投訴我,
send me to the principal's office.
God must be saying that he wants to discipline me
because of my messy life.
糟糕,我這麼吵,他一定要罰我了。
But on the other hand, Norman was so excited, yeah!
但在第二方面,Norman就極興奮。
Because he said, wow, God must be giving me some award
and giving me praises, I'm doing so well.
哇,神啊,我知道啦,一定要頒個獎給我啦,我做得這麼好。
He was so proud.
我真是,啊,me.
So that night, both of them could not sleep well.
唉,那晚,他們兩個都睡得不好。
Sydney was very scared.
Sydney就好驚啦。
Norman was very excited.
Norman就太興奮啦。
And then the next day,
然後第二天了。
Norman woke up really early and dressed well.
Norman就好早起身啦,就打扮得好企理。
And he went to God's house.
咁佢呢,就去到神嘅屋企嗰度。
When he was on the way going to God's house,
he saw people around,
哎呀,they are of such low standard pick.
咁Norman一路去緊神嘅屋企嘅時候,
佢見到其他嘅豬,
唉,不屑呀,真係,嚟睇下都唔想呀。
God must be really pleased as I compare to the rest of these pigs.
大神對我,睇我梗係唔同啲嘅,
即係高豬一等嘅。
So when he arrived,
咁呀,佢就去啦。
咁呀,去到門口就敲門啦。
God opened the door and welcomed him in.
神呢,就打開門,就歡迎佢入嚟啦。
God smiled to him and said,
神呢,就對住佢笑,就同佢講,
I have a thing I want to tell you.
我有嘢想同你講呀。
First of all, I love you.
第一樣嘢係,我好愛你呀。
Norman smiled, but in his heart he said,
哎呀,I know it, love.
咁Norman呢,就笑笑嘴啦,
咁但係內心就係,我知道啦。
Because I'm such a good pig, of course God loves me.
咁呀諗,梗係啦,我咁乖隻豬,梗係愛我啦。
But then God continued to say,
咁但係神繼續講啦喎。
But I love you is not because of the good things that you have done.
我愛你呢,並唔係因為你所做嘅好事呀。
Norman was surprised.
Norman,Norman就有啲,吓,真係?
And then God continued to say,
咁神又繼續講啦。
Actually you are not as good as you thought.
神就話啦,你知唔知呀,
其實你唔係比你自己想像中咁好㗎咋。
You are proud, you are selfish,
and you look down on other people.
其實你都幾驕傲啦,
你都幾自我忠心啦,
同埋你會睇低別人喎。
Now I tell you,
I love those people as much as I love you.
我想同你講嘅就係,
我愛佢哋好似我愛你咁多。
So from now on, don't look down on anyone of those that I love.
所以由而家開始,
千祈唔好睇低一啲我所愛嘅人呀。
So Norman was sad and confused.
Norman,直情心裡沉一沉,
有啲失望,有啲傷心。
What? I'm not getting any praises or any award from God
and just send home like this?
吓,我以為我今日嚟,
係神會讚我啦,頒個獎畀我啦,
冇㗎咩?
So he walked home very sadly.
咁佢呢,就一路帶住沉重嘅腳步,
好唔開心諗返屋企啦。
And as he was on the street,
as he looked around the people around him,
咁當佢又喺條街上面,
左顧右盼又見到其他嘅朋友嘅時候,
and for the first time he noticed that he was really proud
because he looked down on those people all the time.
第一次呢,佢發現自己呢,
真係佢就睇低其他人,
自己係真係好驕傲啦。
He felt so shameful about himself,
and the tears rolled down his face.
佢呢,覺得自己真係好慚愧呀,
咁佢就喊起上嚟呀。
Sidney was watching his neighbor at the window seat.
咁呢,Sidney呢,就喺屋裏面呀,
喺個窗度裝啦,就見到佢鄰居喎。
Oh my goodness, award-winning Norman even came home.
He was such a good man, now he came home in tears.
哎呀,點解呀,Norman好豬嚟㗎,
點解佢返嚟嘅時候,哭曬嘅,咁我點呀?
What happened to me when I go to see God?
So when he walked down the street going to God's house,
he walked so slowly because just like he was going to the principal office,
he was so nervous and sad.
佢真係每一步都覺得好重咁樣呢,
就要行去神奇屋企,就好似以前行去校長室一樣呀。
So when he arrived there,
咁佢又去到神奇屋企啦,佢就敲門啦。
and God opened the door, smiled to him.
咁神呢,就打開門同佢笑笑啦。
Unexpectedly, God said, "I want to tell you something."
神呢,就話,我有嘢想同你講呀。
First of all, Sidney, I love you.
Sidney,我愛你。
Sidney said, "Really? You love me even when I was such a bad pig?"
Sidney said, "What? Me? Such a bad pig? Love me?"
And then God continued to say, "Secondly, I love you."
第二,我想同你講係,我愛你呀。
Sidney was even more surprised.
Really, God loved me and repeated it twice?
Sidney said, "What? Really? You said it twice?"
And then thirdly, I love you.
神又話啦,我要再同你講,第三就係,我愛你呀。
So Sidney was very surprised and stepped out of God's house.
Sidney就話啦, "蛤?我?神愛我?"
咁佢就離開啦。
It must be, I dress up really well today.
或者我今日係咪比較企理咗少少呢?
And when he was walking pass by a store at the window, he looked at the reflection.
咁佢就行過呢,喺條街度行過一間鋪頭,
有個窗就見到自己嘅倒影,佢就望一望自己喎。
Oh, not really, the ketchup mark is still on my tie.
哎呀,其實真係好污糟,好撈教呀,仲見到啲ketchup喺度嘅。
So how come God say he loves me three times?
點解神咁重要嘅事情講三次要同我講,我愛你呢?
但我真係好唔值得被愛喎。
That's only one possibility.
God loves me, even though I made many mistakes, he still loves me the way I am.
個可能性就係,就算我有幾多嘅錯,神一樣咁愛我。
Suddenly he remembered the warmth he saw in God's eyes.
佢突然之間,佢就記得啦,當佢望住神嘅時候,見到神嘅眼其實係充滿咗溫暖。
So tears also rolled down his face.
而佢亦都係咁樣流淚咁樣行返屋企。
So the next day, the two pigs came off the house almost at the same time.
咁第二日啦,終於見面啦,兩個豬仔喺門口度就見到啦。
As they smiled, they greeted.
咁佢哋就畀錢微笑,亦都係打個招呼咁樣啦。
兩隻豬,我哋。
Norman, he was no longer a proud pig anymore that looked down on his neighbor Sidney.
Norman 就唔再係一隻好驕傲自大嘅豬或者會睇低人嘅豬啦。
He gave Sidney a genuine smile and from the bottom of his heart.
佢對住Sidney真係有一個從心底發出嚟好真嘅一個嘅微笑。
而Sidney did not stare at the ground and be so shameful of himself anymore。
而Sidney亦都唔會淨係會望住嘅地下就覺得好自殘營位咁樣。
He has his head up with self-confidence because he knows that God loves him.
因為佢可以舉起個頭嚟,佢充滿自信,係因為神愛佢。
And then both pigs become good friends because they know that God loves both of them the same even though they were different.
從此兩隻豬就成為咗好朋友啦,因為佢哋都知道神愛佢哋。
Even though they were different.
雖然佢哋唔一樣,但神畀佢哋愛都係一樣。
So after hearing the story,
喺聽完個故事之後,
Will you identify yourself as Sidney or will you identify yourself as Norman?
你究竟覺得自己係似Norman多啲呀定似Sidney多啲呀?
If you think that you can identify yourself as Sidney,
then would you think that really no one likes me?
如果你覺得自己似Sidney多啲嘅時候,你會唔會有時都覺得其實都冇乜人鍾意我?
Including God.
我覺得神都唔係好鍾意我啦。
Do you think that we always run into troubles and mess things up?
因為我成日都會去找麻煩啦,或者搞到一團糟啦。
We are good at nothing and we have done so many things that people say that we are disgusting or we disappoint people.
或者我哋做咗好多嘅嘢呢,其他人對我哋都係好失望嘅,鬧咁搞嘅。
We disappoint our parents, our siblings, our husband, our wife, our children, our friends, our teachers, our boss.
因為我哋會令到啲,我哋令到老師啦,老闆啦,我嘅父母啦,我嘅子女啦,我嘅配偶啦,都係失望。
The story is not just for children, but for everyone of us here in this room.
呢個故事唔係淨係for 小朋友嘅,呢個故事係畀我哋呢個電鐘裏面每一個人㗎。
Do we think that we don't deserve God's love?
你係咪咁諗啊,我簡直唔配得神嘅愛。
Even though we are already a Christian, but we still always mess up our life.
因為我哋雖然係已經成為基督徒啊,但係好多時我哋都會做錯事,我哋都會搞到我哋嘅生命一團糟,神梗係唔愛我啦。
We think that we don't deserve God's salvation for us at all, and we have self-pity.
我哋呢簡直唔配得神嘅愛,我哋呢就會自戀。
But then maybe we are the opposite, that we identify ourselves as Norman.
但係有時我哋話好似Norman咁樣㗎喎。
We think that we are such a perfect person that no one can find any fault in us.
或者我哋會睇自己,其實我都幾好啊,幾完美啊,第二啲人應該搵唔到一啲咩錯處。
Do we always receive applause or praises from our parents, our teachers, our boss, our friends, everyone around us?
我哋好似由細至大,老師啦,我嘅老闆啦,我嘅配偶啦,我嘅父母啦,我嘅子女啊,都係要讚賞我同埋俾掌聲我嘅。
We think that we are better than other people and look down on them.
我哋會覺得我哋自己比其他人都好啦,我哋就會睇低別人。
Some of you may be even going to Christian school since you were in kindergarten.
或者我哋當中有啲人或者小朋友由幼稚園就開始去基督教學校㗎啦。
You know Bible so well.
你實在認識聖經真係好叻㗎。
You think that God loves you because of the good knowledge you had about the Bible in your head?
你諗,因為我識聖經好多,讀聖經又好多,所以神愛我。
We may have received a lot of trophies and awards and even public recognitions that we become proud.
或者我屋企擺咗好多獎狀,好多獎牌,喺公眾面前亦都得到好多讚賞,我個心裏面就好驕傲啦。
Even though we may think that sound like we are very humble and very religious.
或者有時我哋講出嚟,表現出嚟好似好謙卑,都唔係啫。
Maybe even we are a church leader, we are a deacon or even a pastor.
但係甚至係牧者,甚至係我哋嘅領袖。
Are we proud and look down on other people? Just think that God loves us because we are good.
我哋有冇真係去睇低別人,我哋諗神愛我,因為我做得好囉。
We are self-righteous and prideful, like Norman.
It reminded me of the Bible story in John 8,1,11 that we have just read.
亦都令我記得聖經裏面一個故事,就係約翰福音第八章一至十一節。
Well, one day, the Pharisees and the teachers dragged a woman over to Jesus.
有一日,民時同范麗卓人直情拉住一個女人,就嚟到主耶穌面前。
That woman was caught in bed with a man that is not her husband.
佢哋就話呢個女人犯咗姦淫,就係正正犯緊事嘅時候俾我哋捉到。
So they dragged this woman to Jesus and said, "Hey, Jesus, you look at this woman."
所以佢哋就拖咗呢個女人嚟到主耶穌面前,主耶穌,你睇下呢個女人。
According to the law of Moses, she should be stoned to death. What do you think about this?
民時法理卓人就話,根據摩西嘅律法,佢應該被石頭打死。你點睇?
And then Jesus, without answering him, just stooped down and used his fingers to write on the ground.
主耶穌就冇答佢哋,主耶穌就靜靜跪低,就喺地面上寫字。
So these people, these Pharisees, asked Jesus again.
咁呢啲民時法理卓人又再一次問主耶穌。
What do you think? What should we do with this woman?
你覺得應該點做?我哋應該點樣對待呢個女人呢?
In fact, they just want to catch, trick Jesus, want to catch him saying something wrong, so they can have it against him.
其實呢,呢班民時同法理卓人呢,係淨係想捉主耶穌嘅把柄。
如果佢有啲嘢講錯呢,就可以定佢有罪。
Jesus looked up and said, "Anyone that have not sinned can be the first one to pick up a stone and stone this woman."
如果你哋中間,你知道冇罪嘅,你可以首先用石頭打死佢。
You know what? 你覺得點呢?
Those Pharisees and leaders, they dare not do it. They left one by one.
原來呢啲民時同法理卓人冇一個敢去咁樣做。
Because on second thought, all of them did have sinned.
因為佢哋諗一諗嘅時候,佢哋實在知道佢哋每一個都犯過罪。
And then when finally all have left and just left with the woman and Jesus,
當所有人都走曬嘅時候,淨低主耶穌同埋呢個女人。
Jesus asked the woman, "So where are those men?"
主耶穌就問呢個女人, "咦,啲人去曬邊呀?"
The woman said, "They have all left."
個女人話, "佢哋走曬喇。"
So no one condemned you?
主耶穌話, "冇人定你嘅罪咩?"
No one.
冇呀。
And God said, Jesus said, "I don't condemn you too. Just don't sin anymore."
主耶穌就話, "咁,我都唔定你嘅罪啦。你走啦,你以後唔好再犯罪啦。"
Actually those Jewish teachers and also the Pharisees are like Norman.
其實嗰啲嘅民事法理初人就好似Norman咁樣。
They think so highly of themselves because they were proud and looked down on everyone.
因為佢哋覺得自己好好呀,佢哋睇低其他人呀。
They only recognized someone's sins, but they didn't see their own sins. They were also sinners.
佢哋淨係見到其他人嘅罪呀,見唔到自己嘅罪呀。
That woman was just the opposite. She was like Sidney. She was so shameful about herself.
而呢個女人就好似Sidney咁樣呀,佢就好似成日都低低頭嗰啲諗住自己有幾多罪呀。
And then she thought that she will be rejected by God too.
佢喺度諗,連神都會唔要佢嘅。
Let me show you something.
我又想畀大家睇一啲嘢。
What is this thing?
你知唔知呢樣嘢係咩嚟嘅?
Wow, beautiful necklace.
好似一條好長嘅頸鏈。
And I have a pair of scissors.
我有一把剪刀。
I'm not going to do it, but I'm just asking you.
但我唔係會做嘅,不過我會咁樣問。
Too expensive and precious to me.
太靚啦呢條頸鏈。
If I use this scissors, chop chop chop chop chop chop chop at ten different points, what will happen?
如果我用呢筆剪刀,將呢條頸鏈剪十次,你會覺得有啲乜嘢嘅發生?
Oh, the beautiful, all the pearls, the beads will come out, right?
即係散晒。
散晒。
But if I use the scissors, I just cut it only, only at one point, what will happen?
但如果我只搵把剪刀剪一個地方啫,你又會覺得會點呢?
Still 散晒。
都係散晒。
So whether we have ten thousand sins, or whether we have only one sin, and that is still sin.
當我哋覺得自己好似犯咗一個罪,或者犯咗十個罪,好多嘅罪,其實都係罪。
Before God, we are still a sinner.
喺神面前,我哋每一個都係罪人。
So we all deserve eternal death, separated from God forever and ever and ever.
係我哋抵,我哋有呢個叫永死嘅其實。
So we have to think, are we really Sydney, or are we Norman?
所以我哋就諗啦,我係Norman,定我係Sydney呢?
So now, I want everyone to close your eyes, including children, adults, and you and everyone.
我哋都喺現在呢,就去閉埋你嘅眼,無論你大,無論你細,都閉埋你嘅眼。
So be very quiet.
你會可以好安靜喺神面前。
So you think, if you are Sydney, whether you are a Christian or not.
或者你係基督徒,或者你唔係基督徒。
Do you think that you have made such a mess in your life that you can never be forgiven by Jesus?
或者你生命實在一團糟,以致唔會得到原諒呢?
Do you think that everyone is rejecting you, including God?
你有冇覺得所有人都喺度,嫌棄你,包括神呢?
If so, please say a silent prayer to apologize to God now, asking for forgiveness.
如果你係咁樣諗,你就現在安靜喺神面前祈禱。
你向祂認罪,向祂悔改。
Because no sin is bigger than Jesus' salvation.
因為我哋冇一個嘅罪係大過主耶穌俾我哋嘅救恩。
God says to you, "I love you regardless of your mess and mistakes."
神話,就算我見到你嘅罪,你嘅錯,我都愛你。
I will forgive you.
我會寬恕你。
Now use one minute to say a silent prayer.
讓我哋用一分鐘嘅時候向主耶穌,向神,去認罪悔改。
Or maybe you are like Norman, whether you are Christian or not.
或者你覺得自己係Norman,無論你係基督徒或者唔係基督徒。
You may even be a church key leader, or a deacon, or a pastor.
你甚至係教會嘅領袖執事牧者。
Be honest to God.
同喺神面前我哋要坦誠。
Are we like Sidney, thinking very highly of ourselves, that we look down on other people like a Pharisee?
我哋會唔會好似Norman咁去睇低其他人,就好似啲民事法理賽人咁樣呢?
Even though you have been in Christian school and always get the award from your school principal,
are you like Sidney, very proud of yourself?
或者我哋由細至大都會有攞好多獎嘅,
但係我哋會唔會好似Norman咁樣好驕傲呢?
Sometimes do we always even put ourselves equal to God, thinking that we manage everything well with our own talents?
或者我哋甚至有冇時候會諗到我哋可以同神平起平坐咁樣呢?
We can manage everything with our own talents, our wisdoms and strength.
或者我可以處理哂我所有嘅事情,我有好大嘅力量可以處理。
We can manage things with our power, with our money and networking with our God.
因為我有足夠嘅能力,金錢,我可以處理哂我自己嘅事情。
Are we willing to confess our pride and self-righteousness, just like Norman or that adultery woman?
我哋又願唔願意去到神自己嘅面前謙卑落嚟認我哋嘅自己嘅罪,求佢嘅寬恕呢?
Now also use one minute to say a silent prayer and ask God to forgive us.
亦都讓我哋用一分鐘嘅時候向神祈禱。
The power of the heart is the most important thing.